Guide to the Doris Duke Foundation records, 1934-2009 (bulk 1948-1982)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Doris Duke Foundation records 1934-2009 (bulk 1948-1982)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Doris Duke Foundation
45 linear feet Extent: 30,755 Items
The Doris Duke Foundation, Inc., formerly known as Independent Aid, Inc., was incorporated in 1934 as a philanthropic organization to operate for charitable, educational, and scientific purposes. In October 1951, the officers of Independent Aid, Inc. voted to change its name to the Doris Duke Foundation. At the time of this change, the foundation's interests were primarily in the fields of education and welfare. The materials in this collection illustrate Doris Duke’s devotion to philanthropy as well as her many varied interests. Some of the major topics represented in the Donation Files are poverty, the disabled, education, health care, animal welfare, underprivileged children, and the performing arts. The Doris Duke Foundation continues to exist as a private grant-making entity.
RL.00318
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research, however there are restrictions on certain materials within the collection. See Series level descriptions for more information.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Doris Duke Foundation Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a donation from the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation in June 2009.
Historical Note
The Doris Duke Foundation, Inc., formerly known as Independent Aid, Inc., was incorporated in 1934 as a philanthropic organization to operate for charitable, educational, and scientific purposes. Doris Duke decided when she reached her majority to organize a foundation in order to deal with the many requests for aid addressed to her. She reasoned that a wisely selected board of directors, by reason of their broad experience, could act with her in reaching objective decisions on appeals for assistance. Doris Duke's idea at the start had been to help people to help themselves, either by offering opportunities for education or for retraining or financial assistance during a period of stress due to illness, unemployment, unexpected family burdens and the like. In October 1951, the officers of Independent Aid, Inc. voted to change its name to the Doris Duke Foundation. At the time of this change, the foundation's interests were primarily in the fields of education and welfare. It did not operate directly, but made grants to other organizations and institutions. The Doris Duke Foundation was supported directly by Doris Duke until her death in 1993. The Doris Duke Foundation continues to exist as a private grant-making entity.
Collection Overview
The Doris Duke Foundation records (formerly DDF.9) is part of the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation Historical Archives which were donated to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library by the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation. The collection is arranged into three series: Administrative Records, Financial Records, and Subject Files. It primarily spans the years 1934–2009, although the bulk of the collection is concentrated from the late 1940s–1982. The records illustrate Doris Duke’s devotion to philanthropy as well as her many varied interests. Some of the major topics represented in the Donation Files are poverty, the disabled, education, health care, animal welfare, underprivileged children, the performing arts (including musical prodigies Lorin Maazel and Dike Newlin), refugees, and various community services. Two topics of great interest to Miss Duke were spirituality and American Indians. This is illustrated by the extensive files on the Self-Realization Fellowship Church and the American Indian Oral History Project. Doris Duke’s own notations are sometimes found in the Subject Files series, demonstrating her very close involvement with the foundation. Geographically there is a focus on “local” organizations based in areas connected with the Duke Family. These include New York City, New Jersey, North Carolina, Rhode Island, and Hawaii. Several international organizations are also represented.
From the 1930s until the mid-seventies the records were maintained at the Doris Duke Foundation’s (also Independent Aid, Inc.’s) office in New York City (New York Business Office was located at 30 Rockefeller Plaza until 1971 when it was relocated to 505 Park Avenue). In March 1975 the Duke Business Office moved to the New Jersey estate, and records from that point on were maintained at Duke Farms.
The records appeared to have been maintained by the Executive Secretary-Treasurer of the Foundation. These include Marion Paschal beginning in the 1930s/early 1940s until her death in 1946 (although according to the records Clarence E. Pickett served as Executive Secretary during this time period, M. Paschal might have been Treasurer or had a different administrative title); Georgea T. Furst from 1946–1953 (from 1943–1946 she served as Assistant to the Executive Secretary and Board Member Clarence E. Pickett); Sophia van Theis from 1953–1957; and May E. McFarland from 1957 until 1975. After the move to New Jersey the records were maintained by Elisabeth McConville (although she appears to have had a purely secretarial, not executive, position, that role seems to have been taken on by A.E. Searles).
Subject Headings
Duke, Doris, 1912-1993; Independent Aid, Inc.; Doris Duke Foundation; Charitable foundations; Philanthropy and society
Related Material
Independent Aid, Inc. records, 1934-1954
Duke University Archives/David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Contents of Collection
- Administrative Records, 1949-2001
  This series contains an assortment of materials related to the business activities of the Doris Duke Foundation. Materials include correspondence related to various grant requests for donations (both from individuals and other charitable organizations) to the Doris Duke Foundation (DDF), lists of contributions made by the DDF, contributions made by the DDF, and general correspondence of the DDF related to regular business activities including meeting minutes, leases, and amendments to the by-laws. Also included in this series are grant requests to the foundation after the death of Doris Duke.
  The materials are arranged in the order in which they were found
  RESTRICTED: Access to folders in boxes 4 and 5 are restricted and require prior written approval from the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation to view.
  - Correspondence regarding donations made by DDF to the North Carolina Museum of Art and St. Georges School in Newport, R.I. 1962, 1970–1973, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and project proposals of the Newton Foundation Inc., Beverly Hills, CA. Materials demonstrate the Newton Foundation’s endeavor to secure funding from the Doris Duke Foundation located at 41 E. 57th Street, 1966–1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memorandum listing financial requests made to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1978 Oct 27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence relating to requests for donations to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and lists relating to various requests made for donations from DDF, 1982 (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and lists relating to various requests made for donations from DDF, 1982 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence regarding donations requested by the New Jersey Conservation Foundation, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence regarding donations requested from God’s Love We Deliver and the Newport Public Education Foundation, 1987, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Memorandum to Doris Duke Foundation requesting donations, 1990, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sample correspondence relating to replies to grant requests, 1992–1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and memoranda relating to grant recommendations from Betsy Fader, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence relating to DDF community grants, 1998–2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Legal Agreement between DDF and the Near East Dance Foundation to finance a film by Mounir Maassri starring Nadia Gamal, 1971–1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - List of contributions of DDF, 1942–1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - List of contributions of DDF, 1951–1996 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - List and correspondence regarding various contributions made by DDF, 1979–1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - List and correspondence regarding various donations made by DDF, 1983 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - List and correspondence regarding various donations made by DDF, 1983 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - List and correspondence regarding various donations made by DDF, 1984–1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - List, international grants, DDF, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - List, contributions of DDF, 1996–1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - List, contributions of DDF, 1998–2000 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Booklet, Center for American Living, “Citizens for Justice with Order.” Possibly sent to DDF in order to request a donation, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence relating to grants to Alvin Ailey American Dance Theater, 1968–1973, 1994–1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence relating to donations to the American Foundation for A.I.D.S. Research (A.M.F.A.R.), 1993–1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence relating to donations to the American Red Cross, 1981, 1994–1996 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence relating to donations to the Association for Retarded Citizens (A.R.C.), 1993-1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence relating to donations to the Atlantis Foundation, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence relating to donations to Aunt Bee’s, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence relating to donations to Big Brothers/Big Sisters of Bergen and Passaic, Inc., 1975, 1994–1996 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence relating to donations made to Bonnie Brae Foundation, 1983, 1994–1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence relating to donations made to Boys Harbor, 1954, 1970, 1993–1996 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Brearley School, N.Y.: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Breast Cancer Resource Center, Princeton Y.M.C.A.: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Cedars-Sinai Medical Center: Donations. Includes 1971 IRS exemption, 1993–1994 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Cesar E. Chavez Foundation: Donations, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Chances for Children: Donations, 1995–1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Children’s Aid and Family Services, Inc., 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cumberland College: Donations. Includes 1976 IRS exemption, 1993–1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Duke Ellington Scholarship Fund N.Y.: Donations, 1993–1994, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Elizabeth Taylor A.I.D.S. Foundation: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Elton John A.I.D.S. Foundation: Donations, 1993–1995 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - First Aid and Rescue Squad, Somerville: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - First Baptist Church of Nutley, N.J.: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Food Bank Network of Somerset County: Donations. Includes 1983 IRS exemption, 1994–1996 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Franklin Township Food Bank: Donations. Includes 1983 IRS exemption, 1994–1996 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Friends of Karen: Donations, 1994–1995 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Greyhound Pets of America: Donations. Includes 1968 IRS exemption, 1993–1998 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Hale House Center, Inc.: Donations, 1973, 1994–1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Heal the World: Donations, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - H.E.L.P.: Donations, 1994–1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Hillsborough Boys Football Assn., Belle Meade, Little Dukes: Donations,1993–1998 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Hillsborough Fire Co. No. 1, Flagtown: Donations. Includes 1990 tax exemption, 1993–1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Hillsborough Fire Co. No. 2, Somerville: Donations. Includes 1967 tax exemption, 1993–1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Hillsborough/Millstone Municipal Alliance: Donations. Includes 1972 tax exemption, 1994–1996 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hillsborough Rescue Squad: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hollywood For Children Fund, Audrey Hepburn: Donations, 1994–1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Homeless Solutions: Donations. Includes 1993 IRS exemption, 1994–1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Honolulu Fire Department: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Honolulu Police Relief Association: Donations. Includes 1955 IRS exemption, 1993–1996 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Horticultural Society, N.Y.: Donations. Includes 1975 IRS exemption, 1993–1996 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Interfaith Hospitality Network, Somerville: Donations. Includes 1991 IRS exemption, 1994–1996 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - International Disaster Emergency Services c/o Wood-Mizer Products: Donations, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - International Rescue Committee (Ambassador Angier Biddle Duke): Donations, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Manville First Aid & Rescue Squad: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Marimed Foundation, Hawaii: Donations. Includes 1984 Dept. of Treasury letter, 1993–1996 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance, Inc.: Donations, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Access restricted
  - Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance, Inc.: Donations, 1994, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The M.B.F. Center: Donations. Includes 1992 IRS exemption, 1994–1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Meals on Wheels in Hunterdon, Inc.: Donations, 1994–1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Megan’s Place Fund: Donations, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Methodist Home for Children: Donations, 1994–1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, N.Y.: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - M.J.J. Enterprises, Michael Jackson: Donations, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Monmouth Day Care Center: Donations. Includes 1969 IRS exemption, 1994–1996 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Municipal Art Society of N.Y. (Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis Award): Donations. Includes 1977 IRS exemption, 1994–1996 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Naval Foundation, Washington, D.C.: Donations. Includes 1977 IRS regulations, 1993–1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - New Jersey Vietnam Veterans’ Memorial Foundation: Donations, 1994–1996 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - New Jersey Wheelchair Athletic Association: Donations, 1985, 1988–1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Newport Fire Department: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Newport Police Department: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Newport Restoration Foundation: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - New York Public Library: Donations. Includes 1968 and 1988 IRS Regulations, 1993–1996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - New York University: Donations. Includes a legal Agreement regarding donations made to N.Y.U. by DDF (January 24, 1958), 1958–1977 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Ocean’s Harbor House: Donations. Includes 1988 IRS exemption, 1994–1996 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Orange County Works: Donations. Includes 1994 IRS exemption, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Orentreich Foundation for the Advancement of Science Inc.: Donations, 1994–1996 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - P.B.A. Local 205, Hillsborough Township: Donations, 1995–1996 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Pennsylvania Ballet; Donations. Includes 1992 IRS Exception, 1995–1996 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (P.E.T.A.): Donations, 1992–1995 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Plan New Jersey: Donations, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Planet Hope: Donations, 1994–1996 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Police Department, Borough of Raritan: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Police Department, Hillsborough Township: Donations. Includes 1972 IRS exception, 1993–1996 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Potter League for Animals. Newport, R.I.: Donations. Includes 1994 IRS tax exceptions, 1993–1998 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Relief Hose Company No. 2, Borough of Raritan: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Research to Prevent Blindness, N.Y.: Donations, 1993–1998 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Resource Center for Women and Their Families: Donations. Includes 1980 IRS exemption, 1993–1996 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - R.O.A.R. Foundation: Donations. Includes 1985 IRS tax exemption, 1993–1996 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Foundation: Donations, 1994–1996 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Salvation Army, Somerset Unit: Donations. Includes 1972 and 1995 IRS tax exemption, 1994–1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - School of American Ballet Inc.: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Self-Realization Fellowship Church: Donations. Includes 1936 IRS tax exemption, 1993–1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Somerset County 4-H Association, Belle Mead: Donations, 1993–1998 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Somerset County Office on Aging: Donations, 1994–1996 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Somerset Home for Temporarily Displaced Children, Bridgewater: Donations. Includes 1970 IRS tax exemption, 1994–1996 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Somerset Medical Center: Donations. Includes 1994 IRS tax exemption, 1993–1996 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Somerset Valley Visiting Nurse Association, Inc.: Donations, 1993–1996 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Somerset Valley Y.M.C.A.: Donations. Includes 1990 tax exemption, 1993–1998 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Spaulding for Children: Donations. Includes 1971 IRS tax exemption, 1994–1996 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - St. Hubert’s Animal Welfare Center: Donations. Includes 1940 IRS tax exemption, 1993–1998 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - U.C.L.A.: Donations, 1994–1997 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - United Cerebral Palsy of North Carolina: Donations. Includes 1961 tax exemption, 1993–1996 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - United States Figure Skating Association: Donations. Includes correspondence from a recipient of the donation, Robin Fisher, 1981–1984 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - United Way of Somerset County: Donations. Includes 1983 IRS tax exemption, 1993–1996 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - University of Pennsylvania, The School of Veterinary Medicine: Donations. Includes 1987 IRS tax exemption, 1993–1998 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Wildlife Conservation Society: Donations, 1994–1996 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Women’s Prison Association and Home Inc.: Donations. Includes 1984 IRS tax exemption, 1993–1996 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Invitations to Bernard Lafferty as President of the Doris Duke Foundation, 1994-1996 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - General donation correspondence to and from the Doris Duke Foundation, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence to and from the Doris Duke Foundation regarding the passing of Doris Duke, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - General donation correspondence to and from the Doris Duke Foundation, 1994 (1 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - General donation correspondence to and from the Doris Duke Foundation, 1994 (2 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - General donation correspondence to and from the Doris Duke Foundation, 1994 (3 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - General donation correspondence to and from the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - General donation correspondence to and from the Doris Duke Foundation, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1994 May (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1994 Jun (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1994 Jul (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1994 Aug (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1994 Sep (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1994 Oct (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1994 Nov (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1994 Nov (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1994 Dec (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1994 Dec (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 Jan (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995Feb (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 Mar (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 Apr (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 May (1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 May (2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 Jun (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 Jul (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 Aug (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 Sep (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 Oct (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 Nov (1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 Nov (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 Dec (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1996 (1 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1996 (2 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Grant requests to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1996 (3 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Various copies of Resolutions, Doris Duke Foundation, 1970-1974 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Amendment to DDF bylaws-resignation at 70 years of age. Includes three resignations, 1956, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence regarding donation of assets to the Newport Restoration Foundation, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation lease, 1975-1978 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Letter regarding the Doris Duke Foundation Board of Directors, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Photocopy of Certificate of Incorporation of Independent Aid, Inc., 1934 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Sublease Agreement, 1975-1978 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation lease, 1972-1975 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Meeting Minutes (Ledger No. 1), 1951-1963 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Minutes of Meetings, 1953-1954, 1961, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and other related materials regarding personnel benefits at the Doris Duke Foundation, 1949-1962 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence related to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1966-1975 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - General correspondence of DDF. Includes appeals, contributions, plans and projects, and by-laws, 1963-1968 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence - Doris Duke Foundation, 1958-1974 (1 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence - Doris Duke Foundation, 1958-1974 (2 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence regarding the Doris Duke Foundation's interest in promoting anti-vivisection, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Master Contribution Lists, 1993-1996 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - DDF Christmas Donations, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Meeting Minutes Ledger, No. 2, 1963-1978 (Oversize-box 13)
  - Contributions made in 1994 - The Doris Duke Foundation, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Contributions made in 1995 - The Doris Duke Foundation, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contribution List, 1993 Oct (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contribution List, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1992 (1 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1992 (2 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 8)